<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Hardware-backup | Eric Duncan]]></title>
  <link href="http://preview.eduncan911.com/category/hardware-backup/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://preview.eduncan911.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-04T13:40:29-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://preview.eduncan911.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Eric Duncan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Wacom Intuos3/4 Is Incompatible With the Lenovo Helix]]></title>
    <link href="http://preview.eduncan911.com/hardware-backup/the-wacom-intuos3-slash-4-is-incompatible-with-the-lenovo-helix.html"/>
    <updated>2014-04-04T10:37:08-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://preview.eduncan911.com/hardware-backup/the-wacom-intuos3-slash-4-is-incompatible-with-the-lenovo-helix</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently abandoned my 14 year dedication to Dell laptops in favor of the
Lenovo Helix ultrabook/tablet.  In doing so, I needed a stylus for the active
digitizer as the one that came with the Helix just isn&rsquo;t going to work for
diagramming and sketching.</p>

<h2>Research: Styluses for the Lenovo Helix</h2>

<p>I had a problem: I was obsessed for days reading every blog, review and comment
and watching every video I could find online to figure out what stylus would work
with the Wacom Active Digitizer that is built into the Helix.</p>

<p>Sadly, I couldn&rsquo;t find a straight answer.</p>

<h2>Wacom ZP501ESE Intuos3 Special Edition Grip Pen</h2>

<p>This is the pen I decided on.  It arrived today and I immediately ripped it open
only to find out it didn&rsquo;t work.  And yes, I removed the OEM stylus cause there is
a switch that disables the digitizer when the pen is inserted to save battery.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>So which one?</h2>

<p>Now that I am armed with new search queries <em>e.g. Lenovo Helix Intuos3 doesn&rsquo;t work</em>,
I&rsquo;ve found new pages with additional info that I wish I&rsquo;d found in the first place.</p>

<p>Usually I am diligent enough to find these errors ahead of time.  But, I failed this
time around and I&rsquo;m having fun writing on my new Octopress blog &ndash; so, why not whip
up a quick post to let others know.</p>

<p>I found <a href="http://forums.lenovo.com/t5/X-Series-Tablet-ThinkPad-Laptops/Wacom-Intuos-4-pen-doesn-t-work-on-Helix/td-p/1153403/page/2">this thread</a>
that was the most helpful in figuring out which stylus to get.  Specifically, this post:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>FYI, the Wacom Penabled Digitizer system is not compatible with Intuos, Cintiq, and Bamboo Tablet pens.</p></p><p><p>Any other Wacom Penabled Tablet PC Pen will work (as mentioned, Series 7 slate, Asus EP121, Lenovo ThinkPad Tablet 2, Lenovo X61 &ndash; X230T series, Fujitsu T900 series, Motion F5t, Wacom Bamboo Feel pens to name just a few).</p></p><p><p>Additionally the Wacom Pen Display Pens will work (eg DTU- series).</p></p><p><p>These pens come in different shapes, sizes and button configurations, but the pen must match up with the digitizer system that is built into the tablet and many people aren&rsquo;t aware that Wacom have different systems.</p></p><p><p>The Penabled system is not as advanced as the Intuos or Cintiq unfortunately (fewer pressure degrees, no tilt angles etc), but still very impressive and useful.</p><footer><strong>Brett Gilbertson &ndash; Microsoft Tablet and Touch MVP <a href="http://forums.lenovo.com/t5/X-Series-Tablet-ThinkPad-Laptops/Wacom-Intuos-4-pen-doesn-t-work-on-Helix/td-p/1153403/page/2">http://forums.lenovo.com/t5/X-Series-Tablet-ThinkPad-Laptops/Wacom-Intuos-4-pen-doesn-t-work-on-Helix/td-p/1153403/page/2</a> Wacom Intuos 4 pen doesn&rsquo;t work on Helix</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>Well, there we have it.  NewEgg, a return is coming!</p>

<p>~E</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
