<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Technology | Eric Duncan]]></title>
  <link href="http://eduncan911.com/category/technology/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://eduncan911.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-13T16:23:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://eduncan911.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Eric Duncan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Look Up]]></title>
    <link href="http://eduncan911.com/technology/look-up.html"/>
    <updated>2014-05-08T09:10:30-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://eduncan911.com/technology/look-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Z7dLU6fk9QY "></iframe></div></p>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>It&rsquo;s not very likely you&rsquo;ll make &ldquo;World&rsquo;s Greatest Dad&rdquo;<br/>If you can&rsquo;t entertain a child without using an iPad.</p></p><p><p>When I was a child I&rsquo;d never be home.<br/><br/>Be out with my friends on our bikes and we&rsquo;d roam.<br/>And wear holes in my trainers and graze up my knees<br/>And build our own clubhouse high up in the trees.</p></p><p><p>Now the park is so quiet it gives me a chill.<br/>See no children outside and the swings hanging still.<br/>There&rsquo;s no skipping, no hopscotch, no church and no steeple.<br/>We&rsquo;re a generation of idiots, smartphones and dumb people.</p></p><p><p></p><footer><strong>Gary Turk <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z7dLU6fk9QY">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z7dLU6fk9QY</a></strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>I remember an NPR segment from around ~2008 when I moved to New York hot on the heels of the 2nd generation iPhone, the 3G.  It talked about our society was already significantly affected by the 1st gen iPhone in that we were becoming a race of robots, always starring down at our smartphone.</p>

<p>It went as far as to say how rude it is to look down at your phone at dinner, or while someone was talking to you.  It made a good case about social interactions > your email, to the point of branding you a jackass if you did it.</p>

<p>That segment (sorry, can&rsquo;t find it) changed my view entirely on social interactions and made me overly conscience on my &ldquo;mobile use&rdquo;, along with observing others and their &ldquo;mobile habits.&rdquo;</p>

<p>I tried not to be the asshole that said, &ldquo;Hey, put down your phone and look at me.&rdquo;  Instead, I used other hints that were in the NPR segment such as when noticing someone is paying attention to their mobile device and not looking at you while you are talking, just pause your sentence.  You&rsquo;ll find out that on average 5 seconds go by until they &ldquo;Look Up.&rdquo; Or, you could simply offer a visual clue that they have to focus on.</p>

<p>I am happy to report that after 6 years of this, I find myself placing my smartphone on the table yes; but, I do not do this to monitor it or look at it.  I do this to get the huge 5" screen bulk + bumper cover out of my pocket so I can sit down.  I place it face down so not to disturb me and to give complete focus to the person(s) I am sitting with.  I am happy to report that some even have had taken notice and started to do the same, even coming back to report to me how it changed their social interactions.</p>

<p>Fast forward to my nearly 3 year old daughter I have now, and this video.  I&rsquo;ve reviewed the results of quite a lot of studies on child raising and these tablets and smartphones.  It basically came down to one thing:</p>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>Make it a learning experience for the child and learn together with them.  Do not use as an entertainment device and do not leave them alone with it.</p></p><p><p></p></blockquote></p>

<p>In addition, I take my daughter to the playground in the park often.  The vast majority of the time, there are no kids &ndash; we are the only ones there.  We experience <em>the swings hanging still</em> all too often &ndash; until we jump into them.</p>

<p>~E</p>

<p><cite>#HatTip ForgetFoo <a href="http://forgetfoo.com">http://forgetfoo.com</a></cite></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Glass Distracting Drivers]]></title>
    <link href="http://eduncan911.com/technology/google-glass-distracting-drivers.html"/>
    <updated>2014-05-05T11:34:09-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://eduncan911.com/technology/google-glass-distracting-drivers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/alltechconsidered/2014/03/24/289802359/does-google-glass-distract-drivers-the-debate-is-on">Does Google Glass Distract Drivers? The Debate Is On</a></p>

<p><img src="/blog/images/Google_Glass_Distracting_While_Driving.jpg" title="Google Glass Driving" ></p>

<p>I have several friends, CEOs, CTOs and even strangers tell me they can talk and drive, they can text and drive, they are good drivers, etc.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve always rebuttaled that the human brain can only focus on a single context, at any given time.</p>

<p><audio preload="none" data-mins="04" data-secs="42" data-title="NPR: Does Google Glass Distract Drivers?">
<source src="http://pd.npr.org/anon.npr-mp3/npr/atc/2014/03/20140324_atc_does_google_glass_distract_drivers_the_debate_is_on.mp3">http://pd.npr.org/anon.npr-mp3/npr/atc/2014/03/20140324_atc_does_google_glass_distract_drivers_the_debate_is_on.mp3</a>" >
Audio player not available in your browser. Please try a newer browser.
</audio></p>

<p>A quote in this story summed it up quite well:</p>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>Earl Miller, a professor of neuroscience at MIT who specializes in multitasking, says this sounds like wishful thinking.</p></p><p><p>&ldquo;You think you&rsquo;re monitoring the road at the same time, when actually what you&rsquo;re doing [is] you&rsquo;re relying on your brain&rsquo;s prediction that nothing was there before, half a second ago — that nothing is there now,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;But that&rsquo;s an illusion. It can often lead to disastrous results.&rdquo;</p></p><p><p>In other words, the brain fills in the gaps in what you see with memories of what you saw a half-second ago. Among scientists, that statement is not controversial. The politics of Google Glass — and where it&rsquo;s worn — clearly is.</p></p><p><p></p><footer><strong>Does Google Glass Distract Drivers? The Debate Is On <a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/alltechconsidered/2014/03/24/289802359/does-google-glass-distract-drivers-the-debate-is-on">http://www.npr.org/blogs/alltechconsidered/2014/03/24/289802359/does-google-glass-distract-drivers-the-debate-is-on</a></strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>Bingo.  And this includes &ldquo;hands-free&rdquo; conversations as well as GPS.</p>

<p>Then again, in 30 years we may evolve to actually have our brains multi-task.</p>

<p><cite>#HatTip ForgetFoo <a href="http://forgetfoo.com">http://forgetfoo.com</a></cite></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bitcoin's IRS-blocking 'Dark Wallet' Launched Today]]></title>
    <link href="http://eduncan911.com/technology/bitcoins-dark-wallet-launched-today.html"/>
    <updated>2014-05-01T14:38:13-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://eduncan911.com/technology/bitcoins-dark-wallet-launched-today</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.coindesk.com/hyper-anonymising-bitcoin-service-dark-wallet-launches-today/">Hyper-Anonymising Bitcoin Service ‘Dark Wallet’ Launches Today</a></p>

<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Ouo7Q6Cf_yc "></iframe></div></p>

<p>I first heard about this Dark Wallet protocol a few months ago when <a href="http://pando.com/2014/03/12/moving-on-up-bitcoin-gets-a-boost-as-new-york-opens-applications-for-virtual-currency-exchange-licenses/">New York state</a> announced they are regulating Bitcoin.  And recently when the <a href="http://www.breitbart.com/Big-Government/2014/04/03/IRS-Retroactively-Taxes-Bitcoin">IRS announced it is retroactively taxing Bitcoin as property</a>, the community brought up the Dark Wallet system again.</p>

<p>I have bitcoin and do not plan on paying any tax on it.  I didn&rsquo;t &ldquo;buy&rdquo; any amount using taxable USD, and don&rsquo;t see a need for &ldquo;regulation.&rdquo;  Trying to tax my Bitcoin is basically using a gun to say I need to pay a tax on the open-source software I write: it has value to a select few, and is completely useless to most.</p>

<p><blockquote><p><img class="<a" src="href="http://media.coindesk.com/2014/05/dark.jpg">http://media.coindesk.com/2014/05/dark.jpg</a>" title="&lsquo;Bitcoin Dark Wallet&rsquo;" ></p></p><p><p>The alpha version of Dark Wallet – the hyper-anonymising bitcoin wallet – goes live today.</p></p><p><p>Created by Amir Taaki and Cody Wilson, Dark Wallet provides new tools for financial privacy, including in-built coin mixing and ‘stealth’ wallet addresses.</p></p><p><p>As well as making it easier for people to disguise their transactions from the government, Dark Wallet is also a torpedo aimed at those in the bitcoin community who have embraced co-operation with regulators.</p></p><p><p>Conceived last year and partly funded by $50,000 raised on Indiegogo, the wallet was developed by unSystem, a collective of anarchist bitcoin developers. It represents an ethos that has been largely excluded from the mainstream discourse around bitcoin.</p></p><p><p>In January of this year, Circle CEO Jeremy Allaire told CoinDesk that bitcoin was “absolutely” moving away from its libertarian roots, and described attempts to avoid the regulation of bitcoin as playing into the hands of “anarchists and criminals”.</p><footer><strong>Hyper-Anonymising Bitcoin Service ‘Dark Wallet’ Launches Today <a href="http://www.coindesk.com/hyper-anonymising-bitcoin-service-dark-wallet-launches-today/">http://www.coindesk.com/hyper-anonymising-bitcoin-service-dark-wallet-launches-today/</a></strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>And I personally liked this little nugget from the related article&hellip;</p>

<p><blockquote><p>If your goals are to create a sort of shadow financial system that runs in offshore jurisdictions and is attractive for anarchists and criminals, then maybe [regulation] is not important.</p><footer><strong>Jeremy Allaire via CoinDesk <a href="http://www.coindesk.com/bitcoin-abandons-anti-establishment-wall-street/">http://www.coindesk.com/bitcoin-abandons-anti-establishment-wall-street/</a></strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>The power to tax involves the power to destroy.</p>

<p>~E</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Microsoft Still Building Their Own CPU?]]></title>
    <link href="http://eduncan911.com/technology/is-microsoft-still-building-their-own-cpu.html"/>
    <updated>2014-04-30T13:40:08-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://eduncan911.com/technology/is-microsoft-still-building-their-own-cpu</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was going through some old posts during my import and found where I mentioned that
<a href="/blog/archives/microsoft-to-build-its-own-cpus.html">Microsoft was to build their own CPUs</a>
for the next-gen Xbox after the 360 &ndash; nearly 8 years ago (yes, the
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Xbox_360">Xbox 360 is almost 9 years old</a>).</p>

<p><blockquote><p>The Xbox One&rsquo;s CPU component brings Microsoft’s architecture of choice back to x86, just like the first-generation Xbox. This time, the company kicked IBM to the curb and opted not to jump into another Intel/Nvidia love triangle. Instead, it put a ring on AMD&rsquo;s finger, tapping the same source for general-purpose and graphics computing IP. At the same time, Sony was courting AMD&rsquo;s semi-custom division as well. Both competitors ended up sharing a bed, but due to NDAs was never caught laying down.</p><footer><strong>Tomshardware <a href="http://www.tomshardware.com/reviews/microsoft-xbox-one-console-review</strong> <cite>3681-3.html">http://www.tomshardware.com/reviews/microsoft-xbox-one-console-review</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>Microsoft had Intel for Xbox 1st gen.  Then IBM for the 2nd gen.  For the 3rd gen Xbox One and PS4, we
all know <a href="http://www.anandtech.com/show/6976/amds-jaguar-architecture-the-cpu-powering-xbox-one-playstation-4-kabini-temash">they went with AMD now</a>.</p>

<p>So this got me thinking&hellip; <a href="http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/people/cthacker/">Chuck Thacker is still at Microsoft</a>.  It does take a while to design and produce your CPU.  I wonder if Microsoft will drop that bomb in the next decade.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s sad because after the Zune fiasco, with Zune software no longer compatible with
the Zune players, I&rsquo;m left with $600 in media players that are worthless and useless
cause I can&rsquo;t sync any music to them.  So I don&rsquo;t think I&rsquo;ll ever go back to
Microsoft products after that.  It was one too many low blows over the last decade.</p>

<p>In related news, a buddy of mine sums up how the Xbox One vs PS4 has played out over the last 6 months:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p>Every time I go to look at new Xbox One releases I regret not buying a PS4 instead.</p>&mdash; Jason Alexander (@jasona) <a href="https://twitter.com/jasona/statuses/460530041789480960">April 27, 2014</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>~E</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
