<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Technology | Eric Duncan]]></title>
  <link href="http://eduncan911.com/category/technology/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://eduncan911.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-12T11:42:53-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://eduncan911.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Eric Duncan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I Fight to Keep MKV as My Media]]></title>
    <link href="http://eduncan911.com/technology/why-i-fight-to-keep-mkv-as-my-media.html"/>
    <updated>2014-07-02T09:57:26-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://eduncan911.com/technology/why-i-fight-to-keep-mkv-as-my-media</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have a fairly high-end home media setup in where I store nearly 500 Blu-ray quality 1080p and 720p movies and dozens of TV shows.  I&rsquo;ve archived all the blu-ray and dvds I&rsquo;ve purchased over the last 15 years into a digital format.</p>

<p>Today I want to share with you my reasons for staying with the format MKV, otherwise known as <a href="http://www.matroska.org/">Matroska</a>, over all of these years in lieu of MP4, MOV, AVI, WMV and so on.</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s wrong with MP4, MOV, AVI, etc?</h2>

<p>Let me start by stating the inherit flaw of these.  I am not going to get into lossless, video quality, etc.  There are 1000s of posts on that.  There&rsquo;s also the fight that WMV won&rsquo;t play on iPads, and the Xbox refusing certain copyrighted encryptions.  No.  None of that.</p>

<p>Instead I want to focus on 1 flaw they all have in common: they are only a single layer of intermixed streams of video and audio, unable to be separated, switched off, or doubled up.</p>

<p>Think about a standard DVD or Blu-ray movie: You have multiple audio tracks including multiple commentaries that makes you want to watch the movie over and over again (I recall watching <em>Alien (1979)</em> multiple times with Sigourney Weaver&rsquo;s commentary, <em>Aliens (1986)</em> is even funnier with Bill Paxton&rsquo;s commentary).  Sometimes there are alternative endings to choose from before you start your movie.  Other times, you may need foreign subtitles for the parts in another language; or, those foreign subtitles are translated incorrectly, and you&rsquo;d rather turn them off and interrupt them yourself.</p>

<p>And there in-lies the problem with a single layer of video and audio in the above mentioned formats: whatever is selected at the time of encoding (English, Japanese subtitles, H264 video stream), is merged into a single layer &ndash; unable to be manipulated, turned off, or changed.</p>

<p>I prefer freedom&hellip;</p>

<h2>It&rsquo;s all about the Matroska Layers</h2>

<p>At the very heart of the Matroska container (aka, file format) is its &ldquo;layer&rdquo; approach which gives it the power to encapsulate as many video, audio and subtitle tracks to your heart&rsquo;s content &ndash; all in their RAW format, unmolested by &ldquo;encoders&rdquo; that have to remix them into a single stream in the other formats.</p>

<p>Want all 5 audio commentaries for <em>Alien (1979)</em>, including the two separate Ridley Scott and Sigourney Weaver tracks?  No problem, the MKV container allows you to store as many audio tracks as you like.</p>

<p>Want the alternative cut and ending to <em>The Abyss (1989)</em> in where the aliens are actually here for a different reason (I won&rsquo;t spoil it here)?  No problem with MKVs.</p>

<p>An MKV file can do this because it essentially is just a <em>wrapper</em> around your raw binary streams (or rips) of H264 video, AAC or FLAC audio, and the subtitle text file(s).  DVDs and Blu-rays store these streams separately &ndash; it is how you can switch audio tracks or alternative endings.  It is only natural that you take these raw streams from these disks, and wrap them in a container of sorts (MKV) to have them all at your fingertips to switch video, audio and languages with a click of the button.</p>

<p>Welcome to Matroska.</p>

<h2>Example: Multiple Camera Angles (multiple video streams)</h2>

<p>One of my favorite DVDs is my <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Peter-Gabriel-Growing-Up-Live/dp/B0000DZ3H4?tag=eduncan911-20"><em>Peter Gabriel&rsquo;s &ndash; Growing Up Live (2003)</em></a>, a live recording in Milan of his <em>Growing Up Tour</em> in 2003.</p>

<p>What&rsquo;s interesting about this DVD (I really wish they would release a blu-ray) is that it has interactive camera angles during multiple titles.  You are able to &ldquo;switch videos streams&rdquo; to a different camera angles.  Pretty cool.</p>

<p>With Matroska, I retained these video angles within the single MKV file I created of the DVD when I ripped it.  Given though, I didn&rsquo;t copy the &ldquo;cue markers&rdquo; overlay from the original DVD viewing.  You kind of have to know when you can change angles, and you can select a different video stream while playing.</p>

<h2>Subtitles</h2>

<p>This one is especially important to my family.  With a spouse of a different nationality, English sub-titles are a near must.</p>

<p>The other formats have to &ldquo;burn-in&rdquo; sub-titles on-top of the video, removing the option to turn it off.  Yes, many decoders allow you to add an .srt file alongside the MP4 and it will overlay the subtitles (if you get the right one, and if it is in sync with its time codes).</p>

<p>Again, thanks to Matroska&rsquo;s layers, this is only a matter of adding (or removing, or reording) the subtitle tracks that are part of the MKV layers.</p>

<p>Don&rsquo;t like the Dutch sub-titles as default?  Reorder them, or remove them.</p>

<h2>MKV is open source and well documented</h2>

<p>That&rsquo;s right.  No copyright or patents to infringe on.  The perhaps most importantly, the container format is very well documented allowing for anyone to create a set of tools themselves.</p>

<p>It is a real shame that the big players ignore this format, and it is up to us end-users to hack our devices to play them.</p>

<h2>A callout to Microsoft, Apple and Google</h2>

<p>Why hasn&rsquo;t MKV gone mainstream?  Why hasn&rsquo;t one of these companies openly embraced this superior format?</p>

<p>The answer is simple: copyright and encryption.  The Matroska does not support either with its free and open container format; and therefore, no media partner (MPAA) will ever support a company that openly embraces a format that splays their precious video and audio for all to see and use.</p>

<h2>Handle it myself</h2>

<p>So that leaves me, a lone person, burdened to create my own Matroska MKV containers myself.  More cumbersome is the annoyance of getting the MKVs to play on multiple devices in different media centers and tables.</p>

<p>It seems every few years I have to <em>re-evaluate</em> my media devices and setup to ensure everything is compatible.  Seems to come around with each new Windows release, since the hunt for decoders and setup starts all over.</p>

<p>Next time, it&rsquo;s Linux once and for all.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lenovo Thinkpad End/Insert Key Swap]]></title>
    <link href="http://eduncan911.com/technology/lenovo-thinkpad-end-slash-insert-key-swap.html"/>
    <updated>2014-07-01T12:01:44-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://eduncan911.com/technology/lenovo-thinkpad-end-slash-insert-key-swap</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://forums.lenovo.com/t5/X-Series-Tablet-ThinkPad-Laptops/Helix-End-Insert-keys-swapped/m-p/1136273/highlight/true#M21181">Lenovo Helix End/Insert Keys Swapped</a></p>

<p>I recently switched from the Dell-exclusive club of laptops over the past 15 years to a ThinkPad.  Specifically, the Lenovo ThinkPad Helix.  It was a unit I have been waiting years for to check all the right boxes.</p>

<p>I haven&rsquo;t been privy to the IBM/Lenovo keyboard wars.  I have always heard great things about the IBM ThinkPad keyboard.  Well, it seems this Lenovo Helix came with the newer style of only one row of Function keys + hardware-specific keys (volume, brightness, etc).  Fine by me as I figured out how to lock in the Function-mode-always (a BIOS option).</p>

<p>But now I had a serious problem when coding/writing long documents&hellip;</p>

<h2>The End/Insert Key was Swapped</h2>

<p>Why in the hell would the End/Insert key swap functions when I lock in the Function-key mode of the F1-F12 keys?</p>

<p>This was almost a deal breaker.  Only after crawling the Lenovo forums (a great place to find hacks for Lenovo) did I stumble onto a Lenovo ThinkPad keyboard hack to <a href="https://forums.lenovo.com/t5/X-Series-Tablet-ThinkPad-Laptops/Helix-End-Insert-keys-swapped/m-p/1136273/highlight/true#M21181">reverse the key functions</a>.  It actually remaps the Windows keyboard layout in the registry, an age-old trick I forgot about over a decade ago!</p>

<h2>Swapping the End/Insert key functions</h2>

<p>Instead of supplying a download of a .reg file, which I am not even sure that GitHub supports, I&rsquo;ll explain the instructions on how to create your own .reg file.</p>

<ul>
<li>Right-click on your desktop, select <code>New -&gt; Text Document</code></li>
<li>Copy and Paste the following into this document, letter by letter.</li>
</ul>


<p>``` text lenovo-helix-end-insert-key-swap.reg <a href="https://gist.github.com/eduncan911/f27808d2bb30982b4da5">https://gist.github.com/eduncan911/f27808d2bb30982b4da5</a>
Windows Registry Editor Version 5.00</p>

<p>[HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SYSTEM\CurrentControlSet\Control\Keyboard Layout]
&ldquo;Scancode Map&rdquo;=hex:00,00,00,00,00,00,00,00,03,00,00,00,52,e0,4f,e0,4f,e0,52,e0,00,00,00,00
```</p>

<ul>
<li>Save the file as <code>lenovo-helix-end-insert-key-swap.reg</code></li>
<li>Double-click it to <code>merge</code> it into your registry.  You will need to be logged in as an Administrator.</li>
<li>Reboot and you&rsquo;re done.</li>
</ul>


<p>Now, the function of the End/Insert will be swapped.</p>

<p>Also, <a href="http://blog.lenovo.com/products/why-you-should-give-in-to-the-new-thinkpad-keyboard">devoted fans of the previous Thinkpad keyboard: you may want to take your anger here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Look Up]]></title>
    <link href="http://eduncan911.com/technology/look-up.html"/>
    <updated>2014-05-08T09:10:30-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://eduncan911.com/technology/look-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Z7dLU6fk9QY "></iframe></div></p>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>It&rsquo;s not very likely you&rsquo;ll make &ldquo;World&rsquo;s Greatest Dad&rdquo;<br/>If you can&rsquo;t entertain a child without using an iPad.</p></p><p><p>When I was a child I&rsquo;d never be home.<br/><br/>Be out with my friends on our bikes and we&rsquo;d roam.<br/>And wear holes in my trainers and graze up my knees<br/>And build our own clubhouse high up in the trees.</p></p><p><p>Now the park is so quiet it gives me a chill.<br/>See no children outside and the swings hanging still.<br/>There&rsquo;s no skipping, no hopscotch, no church and no steeple.<br/>We&rsquo;re a generation of idiots, smartphones and dumb people.</p></p><p><p></p><footer><strong>Gary Turk <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z7dLU6fk9QY">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z7dLU6fk9QY</a></strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>I remember an NPR segment from around ~2008 when I moved to New York hot on the heels of the 2nd generation iPhone, the 3G.  It talked about our society was already significantly affected by the 1st gen iPhone in that we were becoming a race of robots, always starring down at our smartphone.</p>

<p>It went as far as to say how rude it is to look down at your phone at dinner, or while someone was talking to you.  It made a good case about social interactions > your email, to the point of branding you a jackass if you did it.</p>

<p>That segment (sorry, can&rsquo;t find it) changed my view entirely on social interactions and made me overly conscience on my &ldquo;mobile use&rdquo;, along with observing others and their &ldquo;mobile habits.&rdquo;</p>

<p>I tried not to be the asshole that said, &ldquo;Hey, put down your phone and look at me.&rdquo;  Instead, I used other hints that were in the NPR segment such as when noticing someone is paying attention to their mobile device and not looking at you while you are talking, just pause your sentence.  You&rsquo;ll find out that on average 5 seconds go by until they &ldquo;Look Up.&rdquo; Or, you could simply offer a visual clue that they have to focus on.</p>

<p>I am happy to report that after 6 years of this, I find myself placing my smartphone on the table yes; but, I do not do this to monitor it or look at it.  I do this to get the huge 5" screen bulk + bumper cover out of my pocket so I can sit down.  I place it face down so not to disturb me and to give complete focus to the person(s) I am sitting with.  I am happy to report that some even have had taken notice and started to do the same, even coming back to report to me how it changed their social interactions.</p>

<p>Fast forward to my nearly 3 year old daughter I have now, and this video.  I&rsquo;ve reviewed the results of quite a lot of studies on child raising and these tablets and smartphones.  It basically came down to one thing:</p>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>Make it a learning experience for the child and learn together with them.  Do not use as an entertainment device and do not leave them alone with it.</p></p><p><p></p></blockquote></p>

<p>In addition, I take my daughter to the playground in the park often.  The vast majority of the time, there are no kids &ndash; we are the only ones there.  We experience <em>the swings hanging still</em> all too often &ndash; until we jump into them.</p>

<p>~E</p>

<p><cite>#HatTip ForgetFoo <a href="http://forgetfoo.com">http://forgetfoo.com</a></cite></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Glass Distracting Drivers]]></title>
    <link href="http://eduncan911.com/technology/google-glass-distracting-drivers.html"/>
    <updated>2014-05-05T11:34:09-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://eduncan911.com/technology/google-glass-distracting-drivers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/alltechconsidered/2014/03/24/289802359/does-google-glass-distract-drivers-the-debate-is-on">Does Google Glass Distract Drivers? The Debate Is On</a></p>

<p><img src="/blog/images/Google_Glass_Distracting_While_Driving.jpg" title="Google Glass Driving" ></p>

<p>I have several friends, CEOs, CTOs and even strangers tell me they can talk and drive, they can text and drive, they are good drivers, etc.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve always rebuttaled that the human brain can only focus on a single context, at any given time.</p>

<p><audio preload="none" data-mins="04" data-secs="42" data-title="NPR: Does Google Glass Distract Drivers?">
<source src="http://pd.npr.org/anon.npr-mp3/npr/atc/2014/03/20140324_atc_does_google_glass_distract_drivers_the_debate_is_on.mp3">http://pd.npr.org/anon.npr-mp3/npr/atc/2014/03/20140324_atc_does_google_glass_distract_drivers_the_debate_is_on.mp3</a>" >
Audio player not available in your browser. Please try a newer browser.
</audio></p>

<p>A quote in this story summed it up quite well:</p>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>Earl Miller, a professor of neuroscience at MIT who specializes in multitasking, says this sounds like wishful thinking.</p></p><p><p>&ldquo;You think you&rsquo;re monitoring the road at the same time, when actually what you&rsquo;re doing [is] you&rsquo;re relying on your brain&rsquo;s prediction that nothing was there before, half a second ago — that nothing is there now,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;But that&rsquo;s an illusion. It can often lead to disastrous results.&rdquo;</p></p><p><p>In other words, the brain fills in the gaps in what you see with memories of what you saw a half-second ago. Among scientists, that statement is not controversial. The politics of Google Glass — and where it&rsquo;s worn — clearly is.</p></p><p><p></p><footer><strong>Does Google Glass Distract Drivers? The Debate Is On <a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/alltechconsidered/2014/03/24/289802359/does-google-glass-distract-drivers-the-debate-is-on">http://www.npr.org/blogs/alltechconsidered/2014/03/24/289802359/does-google-glass-distract-drivers-the-debate-is-on</a></strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>Bingo.  And this includes &ldquo;hands-free&rdquo; conversations as well as GPS.</p>

<p>Then again, in 30 years we may evolve to actually have our brains multi-task.</p>

<p><cite>#HatTip ForgetFoo <a href="http://forgetfoo.com">http://forgetfoo.com</a></cite></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bitcoin's IRS-blocking 'Dark Wallet' Launched Today]]></title>
    <link href="http://eduncan911.com/technology/bitcoins-dark-wallet-launched-today.html"/>
    <updated>2014-05-01T14:38:13-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://eduncan911.com/technology/bitcoins-dark-wallet-launched-today</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.coindesk.com/hyper-anonymising-bitcoin-service-dark-wallet-launches-today/">Hyper-Anonymising Bitcoin Service ‘Dark Wallet’ Launches Today</a></p>

<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Ouo7Q6Cf_yc "></iframe></div></p>

<p>I first heard about this Dark Wallet protocol a few months ago when <a href="http://pando.com/2014/03/12/moving-on-up-bitcoin-gets-a-boost-as-new-york-opens-applications-for-virtual-currency-exchange-licenses/">New York state</a> announced they are regulating Bitcoin.  And recently when the <a href="http://www.breitbart.com/Big-Government/2014/04/03/IRS-Retroactively-Taxes-Bitcoin">IRS announced it is retroactively taxing Bitcoin as property</a>, the community brought up the Dark Wallet system again.</p>

<p>I have bitcoin and do not plan on paying any tax on it.  I didn&rsquo;t &ldquo;buy&rdquo; any amount using taxable USD, and don&rsquo;t see a need for &ldquo;regulation.&rdquo;  Trying to tax my Bitcoin is basically using a gun to say I need to pay a tax on the open-source software I write: it has value to a select few, and is completely useless to most.</p>

<p><blockquote><p><img class="<a" src="href="http://media.coindesk.com/2014/05/dark.jpg">http://media.coindesk.com/2014/05/dark.jpg</a>" title="&lsquo;Bitcoin Dark Wallet&rsquo;" ></p></p><p><p>The alpha version of Dark Wallet – the hyper-anonymising bitcoin wallet – goes live today.</p></p><p><p>Created by Amir Taaki and Cody Wilson, Dark Wallet provides new tools for financial privacy, including in-built coin mixing and ‘stealth’ wallet addresses.</p></p><p><p>As well as making it easier for people to disguise their transactions from the government, Dark Wallet is also a torpedo aimed at those in the bitcoin community who have embraced co-operation with regulators.</p></p><p><p>Conceived last year and partly funded by $50,000 raised on Indiegogo, the wallet was developed by unSystem, a collective of anarchist bitcoin developers. It represents an ethos that has been largely excluded from the mainstream discourse around bitcoin.</p></p><p><p>In January of this year, Circle CEO Jeremy Allaire told CoinDesk that bitcoin was “absolutely” moving away from its libertarian roots, and described attempts to avoid the regulation of bitcoin as playing into the hands of “anarchists and criminals”.</p><footer><strong>Hyper-Anonymising Bitcoin Service ‘Dark Wallet’ Launches Today <a href="http://www.coindesk.com/hyper-anonymising-bitcoin-service-dark-wallet-launches-today/">http://www.coindesk.com/hyper-anonymising-bitcoin-service-dark-wallet-launches-today/</a></strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>And I personally liked this little nugget from the related article&hellip;</p>

<p><blockquote><p>If your goals are to create a sort of shadow financial system that runs in offshore jurisdictions and is attractive for anarchists and criminals, then maybe [regulation] is not important.</p><footer><strong>Jeremy Allaire via CoinDesk <a href="http://www.coindesk.com/bitcoin-abandons-anti-establishment-wall-street/">http://www.coindesk.com/bitcoin-abandons-anti-establishment-wall-street/</a></strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>The power to tax involves the power to destroy.</p>

<p>~E</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
