<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Technology | Eric Duncan]]></title>
  <link href="http://eduncan911.com/category/technology/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://eduncan911.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-03T13:11:56-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://eduncan911.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Eric Duncan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Authenticator's Databases: Copy, Move and Fix]]></title>
    <link href="http://eduncan911.com/technology/hardware/google-authenticator-databases-move-copy-fix.html"/>
    <updated>2015-08-31T18:03:55-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://eduncan911.com/technology/hardware/google-authenticator-databases-move-copy-fix</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/blog/images/FeatureImage-GoogleAuthenticator.jpg" title="&ldquo;Google Authenticator&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>Google Authenticator is a two-factor application that runs on your mobile or tablet device.  Typically you only run it on one device because the secrets you store in its databases cannot be shared between devices.</p>

<p>In this post, I explain some technical details about this database and how you can exploit the details for your gain (from an Android&rsquo;s perspective).</p>

<h2>Factor Resets</h2>

<p>So when an Android update comes out, I can not update.  I am forced to backup my configurations first, upgrade the device and then restore my configurations after the apps are reloaded.  The reason I have to do this is because I run a custom bootloader.  I also encrypt my device which further mandates a factor reset upon unlocking and locking to regain root access.  What a PITA.</p>

<p>But these annoyances have afforded me the luxury of learning more details about the apps and system processes, along with their configurations.</p>

<p>I use custom bootloaders to gain access to the device in the event of a MMC failure (has happened once, I was able to get important data off of it before it totally was lost).</p>

<p>Encryption is used because, well, I&rsquo;m just <a href="http://motherboard.vice.com/read/fbi-director-if-apple-and-google-wont-decrypt-phones-well-force-them-to">paranoid like that</a>.</p>

<h2>Google&rsquo;s Warning: Stay away from GA&rsquo;s Databases!</h2>

<p>Google has stated (insert ref here) that you should not be copying your Google Authenticator&rsquo;s databases from device to device.  This is true as it could lead to you leaking your secrets by, say, copying the file to your cloud storage to sync to another device.</p>

<p>Not only have you given your cloud provider access to your secrets (that is now backed up and replicated on their systems); but, if hackers gain access to your cloud platform (which several have Undelete options!), that&rsquo;s game over man.</p>

<p>Me?  I always copy directly from my device to a USB stick.  Do my thing on the device and when ready, push it back from the USB stick to my device.  When done, wipe the USB stick (or write an ISO to it, which I do very very often).</p>

<h2>Why Even Bother?</h2>

<p>So why do I go to such extremes?  Google&rsquo;s very own security supplies a way for you to move your secret (a new secret) to a new device, a process I consider the absolute model of perfection of moving your secrets.</p>

<p>One answer: 17.</p>

<p>I have 17 Google Authenticator &ldquo;secrets&rdquo; on my device for 17 services across my personal services and several clients' access.</p>

<p>Have you ever tried to regain access to an account once you lost your two-factor authentication secret?  I have.  I have a 2:5 win/loss ratio when I had to play that game.  No more.</p>

<p>So, it&rsquo;s time to hack this thing to take matters into my own hands.</p>

<p>This, ladies and gentlemen, is why I own Android&hellip;</p>

<h2>Google Authenticator&rsquo;s Database</h2>

<p>If you got Root, then you have more options.</p>

<p>On Android, the Google Authenticator <code>databases</code> file is located at:</p>

<p><code>
/data/data/com.google.android.apps.authenticator2/databases/
</code></p>

<p>Within this directory is a &lsquo;databases&rsquo; file:</p>

<p><code>
root@hammerhead:/data/data/com.google.android.apps.authenticator2/databases # ls -l
-rwxrw-rw- u0_a92     u0_a92        16384 2015-06-22 19:17 databases
</code></p>

<p>And no, that&rsquo;s not a misprint.  There is a directory called <code>databases</code> with a file in it called <code>databases</code>.</p>

<h2>Permissions</h2>

<p>The first dumbfounded thing I found during my first attempt at copying my second version of GA&rsquo;s databases is the permissions.  Take a look closely at the <code>ls</code> command above.  Notice anything?</p>

<p>```
-rwx&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;
User: Read/Write/Execute</p>

<p>&mdash;&mdash;rw&mdash;&mdash;
Group: Read/Write</p>

<p>&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;-rw-
World: Read/Write
```</p>

<p>WTF?  Everyone has access to this file?</p>

<p>During my first restore, I had Google Authenticator constantly crashing on launch.  Come to find out, it did not like my <code>700</code> permissions access I first gave it.  Only after frustration of the app crashing over and over did I just give it full 777 permissions&hellip;  And the app opened without a crash?  It needs world read/write?</p>

<p>I then found out the parent <code>databases</code> directly itself needed the same permissions.</p>

<p>Now, I know that Android has some special user-space for each app to isolate each app&rsquo;s access to the rest of the file system.  Perhaps it&rsquo;s enough to <em>trust</em> Android in that its app isolation is good enough.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t trust anyone with this data; but, unfortunately if you want GA running you have to set the correct permissions at this time:</p>

<p>```</p>

<h1>NOTE: You will need to be &ldquo;su&rdquo; root user to run these</h1>

<p>cd /data/data/com.google.android.apps.authenticator2/
chmod 766 databases
cd databases/
chmod 766 databases
```</p>

<p>The parent <code>databases/</code> folder, and the <code>databases</code> file itself requires world read and write access &ndash; or the Google Authenticator&rsquo;s app won&rsquo;t even open (crashes).</p>

<h2>Ownership</h2>

<p>In addition, and what stemmed me to write this post, is I had another issue.  I was not able to add any new entries to my Google Authenticator.  I had the permissions right, so I thought.</p>

<p>Upon inspection, I could see that the directories surrounding the databases/ directory was owned by a different user.  In my case, that userid was <code>u0_a92</code>.</p>

<p>I am not sure if this was the user space dedicated to this app or not.  But in any case, once I set the owner and group to this user, I was able to add new entries:</p>

<p>```</p>

<h1>NOTE: you will need to be &ldquo;su&rdquo; root user to run these</h1>

<h1>NOTE 2: perform an &ldquo;ls -l&rdquo; like I did above and change u0_a92 to match.</h1>

<p>cd /data/data/com.google.android.apps.authenticator2/
chown u0_a92:u0_a92 databases
cd databases
chown u0_a92:u0_a92 databases
```</p>

<p>And now I was able to add new entries.</p>

<h2>Inspecting the Database</h2>

<p>The <code>databases</code> file itself is a <code>sqlite</code> database.  This makes it easy to write an application to look at the database and query directly against it.</p>

<p><code>
$ sqlite3 ./databases
SQLite version 3.8.11.1 2015-07-29 20:00:57
Enter ".help" for usage hints.
sqlite&gt; .fullschema
CREATE TABLE android_metadata (locale TEXT);
CREATE TABLE accounts (_id INTEGER PRIMARY KEY, email TEXT NOT NULL, secret TEXT NOT NULL, counter INTEGER DEFAULT 0, type INTEGER, provider INTEGER DEFAULT 0, issuer TEXT DEFAULT NULL, original_name TEXT DEFAULT NULL);
/* No STAT tables available */
</code></p>

<p>Here above we can see two tables in this file.  An <code>android_metadata</code> table and an <code>accounts</code> table.</p>

<p>Run this command:</p>

<p><code>
sqlite&gt; SELECT * FROM accounts;
</code></p>

<p>Did you notice everything is in the clear here?  No encryption?</p>

<p>It was so much so that I started to copy and paste my output of 17 accounts; but, it was too much to redact.  I figured I&rsquo;ll just posted the schema above and let you query your own database.</p>

<h2>Takeaways</h2>

<p>There a few things to take away from all of this.</p>

<p>Google Authenticator has world read/write permissions: Is that a security issue?</p>

<p>Google Authenticator stores everything in the clear in Sqlite: Is that a security issue?</p>

<p>I am going to reach out to Google for comment about this one.  But for now, you have the details and know-how to move this file as you see fit.  No more having to reset 17+ accounts, just for an Android update!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[FCC Crashed Again for Net Neutrality]]></title>
    <link href="http://eduncan911.com/technology/fcc/fcc-crashed-again-for-net-neutrality.html"/>
    <updated>2014-07-31T13:56:49-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://eduncan911.com/technology/fcc/fcc-crashed-again-for-net-neutrality</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><audio preload="none" data-mins="01" data-secs="49" data-title="NPR: FCC Extending Net Neutrality Commenting Time After Site Buckles">
<source src="http://pd.npr.org/anon.npr-mp3/npr/me/2014/07/20140716_me_fcc_extending_net_neutrality_commenting_time_after_site_buckles.mp3?dl=1">http://pd.npr.org/anon.npr-mp3/npr/me/2014/07/20140716_me_fcc_extending_net_neutrality_commenting_time_after_site_buckles.mp3?dl=1</a>" >
Audio player not available in your browser. Please try a newer browser.
</audio></p>

<p><blockquote><p>A flood of comments about net neutrality crashed the Federal Communications Commission&rsquo;s commenting site on Tuesday, the original deadline for public comments on the controversial Internet proposal. But the tech problems are buying those who want to weigh in some extra time — the deadline for public commenting is now Friday (July 18th, 2014) at midnight.</p><footer><strong>FCC Extending Net Neutrality Commenting Time After Site Buckles <a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/alltechconsidered/2014/07/15/331798176/fcc-extending-net-neutrality-commenting-time-after-site-buckles">http://www.npr.org/blogs/alltechconsidered/2014/07/15/331798176/fcc-extending-net-neutrality-commenting-time-after-site-buckles</a></strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>Thank you everyone for <a href="/technology/fcc/only-2-days-left-to-crash-the-fcc.html">answering my call to crash the FCC</a>.</p>

<p>Well, at least I&rsquo;d like to think I had a hand in it with my awesome blog posts on the matter.  :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Nexus 10 and Apple Wireless Keyboard]]></title>
    <link href="http://eduncan911.com/technology/hardware/google-nexus-10-and-apple-wireless-keyboard.html"/>
    <updated>2014-07-23T19:50:40-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://eduncan911.com/technology/hardware/google-nexus-10-and-apple-wireless-keyboard</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been fighting an ongoing battle with Apple&rsquo;s Wireless Keyboards and a tablet of mine, the Google Nexus 10.  While the keyboard works with all other Android and Apple devices we have (Nexus 5, Nexus 7 2013, Galaxy Nexus and Apple iPod Touch), it does not work with the Google Nexus 10.  I&rsquo;ve gone as far as to <a href="http://android.stackexchange.com/questions/66496/android-4-4-apple-bluetooth-keyboard-paired-but-not-working">asking for help on SE</a>.</p>

<p>Well, that&rsquo;s not entirely accurate.  The story started with a used Apple Wireless Keyboard I got from eBay.  It paired and worked fine; but, some of the keys did not work.  So I bought a new one from Apple.com.</p>

<p>It paired and connected just fine; but, the brand spanking new keyboard did not work.  The Nexus 10 would not recognize an additional input device (the small &ldquo;A&rdquo; symbol in the top left corner of the screen).</p>

<p>To reiterate, this new Apple Wireless Keyboard ordered direct from Apple.com worked fine with all other Android devices (Android 4.2.2, 4.4.2, 4.4.3 and 4.4.4) and the iPod Touch 4th Gen.  It is only this Nexus 10 (Android 4.4.3 and 4.4.4) that it did not.</p>

<h2>Nexus 10 Bluetooth Stack</h2>

<p>As I blogged some time ago, not all <a href="http://eduncan911.com/blog/archives/bluetooth-expedition-the-right-stuff.html">Bluetooth devices are made equal</a>.   Devices implement the Bluetooth stack differently and sometimes miss an implementation detail.</p>

<p>I highly suspect the Nexus 10 has a flawed Bluetooth implementation, causing this incompatibility.</p>

<p>But what exactly is it incompatible with?  It worked fine with the previous Apple keyboard I got used on eBay.  It works fine with all other bluetooth keyboards I have tried.</p>

<p>Why this one Apple keyboard I got direct from apple.com?</p>

<h2>Apple Wireless Keyboard version: 2007, 2009 and 2011</h2>

<p>Atlas only after several trips to some local Apple stores did I stumble onto the issue: there are three versions of the Apple Wireless Keyboard that were sold.  I found this out by looking at about a dozen different iMacs they had, from old to new.  Surprisingly Apple&rsquo;s newest store located in NYC, in Grand Central Terminal, is the one that had the largest collection of older iMacs &ndash; ones that actually had the 2009 keyboard and even one with the 2007 keyboard.</p>

<p>They are identified by their model years.  To take a quote <a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/ht4112">directly from Apple&rsquo;s support site</a>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>* Apple Wireless Keyboard (2011): Features an aluminum case and uses two AA batteries. You can identify this model by the following icons on the F3 and F4 keys:</p></p><p><p><img src="http://km.support.apple.com/library/APPLE/APPLECARE_ALLGEOS/HT4112/HT4112_01----en.png" /></p></p><p><ul><br/><li>Apple Wireless Keyboard (2009): Features an aluminum case and uses two AA batteries. You can identify this model by the following icons on the F3 and F4 keys:</li><br/></ul></p><p><br/><p><img src="http://km.support.apple.com/library/APPLE/APPLECARE_ALLGEOS/HT4112/HT4112_02----en.png" /></p></p><p><ul><br/><li>Apple Wireless Keyboard (2007): Features an aluminum case and uses three AA batteries.</li><br/></ul></p><p><br/><p></p><footer><strong>Apple Support <a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/ht4112">http://support.apple.com/kb/ht4112</a> &ldquo;Apple Wireless Keyboard compatibility&rdquo;</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>So, we have three keyboards available to us.  After many trials and errors, I can safely say&hellip;</p>

<h2>Get the 2009 Apple Wireless Keyboard model</h2>

<p>The used eBay model I got was a 2009 and it worked fine, dispite a few keys not working.  The Apple.com model I got was an 2011 with the latest x80 firmware &ndash; and it did not work.</p>

<p>You want to focus on the F3 and F4 keys looking like this:</p>

<p><img src="/blog/images/google-nexus-10-and-apple-wireless-keyboard-2009.jpg" title="Nexus 10 and 2009 Apple Wireless Keyboard" ></p>

<p>Again, the 2011 keyboard works fine with all other Android devices, even back to Android 4.2 on my Galaxy Nexus.  So this is clearly a fault with the Nexus 10&rsquo;s bluetooth hardware.</p>

<p>But none the less, if you want an Apple Wireless Keyboard to work with your Nexus 10, you better seek out the 2009 model.</p>

<h2>2009 Apple Wireless Keyboard Firmware</h2>

<p>And btw, the firmware version of the 2009 I found working at an Apple store has firmware version x50.  You can see it under the system&rsquo;s properties, like this:</p>

<p><img src="/blog/images/google-nexus-10-and-apple-wireless-keyboard-2009-firmware.jpg" title="Nexus 10 and 2009 Apple Wireless Keyboard Firmware" ></p>

<p>I only mention the firmware because I found a number of posts online where people upgraded their 2009 and 2011 keyboard firmwares to the latest, and lost some functionality.  I am not sure if the x50 version of the firmware is the latest.  I am only stating the exact version of the 2009 keyboard that worked flawlessly with the Nexus 10.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Only 2 Days Left to Crash the FCC]]></title>
    <link href="http://eduncan911.com/technology/fcc/only-2-days-left-to-crash-the-fcc.html"/>
    <updated>2014-07-13T10:41:03-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://eduncan911.com/technology/fcc/only-2-days-left-to-crash-the-fcc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/alltechconsidered/2014/06/03/318458496/john-oliver-helps-rally-45-000-net-neutrality-comments-to-fcc">John Oliver Helps Rally 45,000 Net Neutrality Comments To FCC</a></p>

<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/fpbOEoRrHyU " frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<p>There&rsquo;s only two days left for comments.  At the time I left mine a month ago, there were 65,000 comments.  Now, there are 205,000.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.fcc.gov/comments">The url to file your comments: fcc.gov/comments</a></p>

<p>The YouTube video hit on every point I&rsquo;ve been saying in person when talking about this, and many more.</p>

<p>One of my biggest I tell people is how the former chairman of the FCC left (forced out?), and the new one put in place by Obama last year previously ran (as in chaired and commanded) the lobbying firm for Cable and Wireless (e.g. Comcast and TimeWarner) which was directly responsible for the last attempt to create the two-tier system that the FCC blocked.  And, that sued the government to force this actual change.</p>

<p>Translation by the current FCC chairman: &ldquo;We didn&rsquo;t win last time. Ok, let&rsquo;s sue the FCC/government to force a rule change. When we win the lawsuit, I&rsquo;ll step down as head of this lobbyist group and become head of the FCC [so I can force this rule through].&rdquo;</p>

<p>How fracked up is that?</p>

<p>Also it sucks that NetFlix already has to pay Comcast to get service to its users.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I Fight to Keep MKV as My Media]]></title>
    <link href="http://eduncan911.com/technology/why-i-fight-to-keep-mkv-as-my-media.html"/>
    <updated>2014-07-02T09:57:26-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://eduncan911.com/technology/why-i-fight-to-keep-mkv-as-my-media</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have a fairly high-end home media setup in where I store my backups of nearly 500 Blu-ray quality 1080p and 720p movies and dozens of TV series on a server with over 20 TB of storage.  I&rsquo;ve archived all the blu-ray and dvds I&rsquo;ve purchased over the last 15 years into a digital format.</p>

<p>Today I want to share with you my reasons for staying with the format MKV, otherwise known as <a href="http://www.matroska.org/">Matroska</a>, over all of these years in lieu of MP4, MOV, AVI, WMV and so on.</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s wrong with MP4, MOV, AVI, etc?</h2>

<p>Let me start by stating the inherit flaw of these.  I am not going to get into lossless, video quality, etc.  There are 1000s of posts on that.  There&rsquo;s also the fight that WMV won&rsquo;t play on iPads, and the Xbox refusing certain copyrighted encryptions.  No.  None of that.</p>

<p>Instead I want to focus on 1 flaw they all have in common: they are only a single layer of intermixed streams of video and audio, unable to be separated, switched off, or doubled up.</p>

<p>Think about a standard DVD or Blu-ray movie: You have multiple audio tracks including multiple commentaries that makes you want to watch the movie over and over again (I recall watching <em>Alien (1979)</em> multiple times with Sigourney Weaver&rsquo;s commentary, <em>Aliens (1986)</em> is even funnier with Bill Paxton&rsquo;s commentary).  Sometimes there are alternative endings to choose from before you start your movie.  Other times, you may need foreign subtitles for the parts in another language; or, those foreign subtitles are translated incorrectly, and you&rsquo;d rather turn them off and interrupt them yourself.</p>

<p>And there in-lies the problem with a single layer of video and audio in the above mentioned formats: whatever is selected at the time of encoding (English, Japanese subtitles, H264 video stream), is merged into a single layer &ndash; unable to be manipulated, turned off, or changed.</p>

<p>I prefer freedom of choice.</p>

<h2>It&rsquo;s all about the Matroska Layers</h2>

<p>At the very heart of the Matroska container (aka, file format) is its &ldquo;layer&rdquo; approach which gives it the power to encapsulate as many video, audio and subtitle tracks to your heart&rsquo;s content &ndash; all in their RAW format, unmolested by &ldquo;encoders&rdquo; that have to remix them into a single stream in the other formats.</p>

<p>Want all 5 audio commentaries for <em>Alien (1979)</em>, including the two separate Ridley Scott and Sigourney Weaver tracks?  No problem, the MKV container allows you to store as many audio tracks as you like.</p>

<p>Want the alternative cut and ending to <em>The Abyss (1989)</em> in where the aliens are actually here for a different reason (I won&rsquo;t spoil it here)?  No problem with MKVs.</p>

<p>An MKV file can do this because it essentially is just a <em>wrapper</em> around your raw binary streams (or rips) of H264 video, AAC or FLAC audio, and the subtitle text file(s).  DVDs and Blu-rays store these streams separately &ndash; it is how you can switch audio tracks or alternative endings.  It is only natural that you take these raw streams from these disks, and wrap them in a container of sorts (MKV) to have them all at your fingertips to switch video, audio and languages with a click of the button.</p>

<p>Welcome to Matroska.</p>

<h2>Example: Multiple Camera Angles (multiple video streams)</h2>

<p>One of my favorite DVDs is my <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Peter-Gabriel-Growing-Up-Live/dp/B0000DZ3H4?tag=eduncan911-20"><em>Peter Gabriel&rsquo;s &ndash; Growing Up Live (2003)</em></a>, a live recording in Milan of his <em>Growing Up Tour</em> in 2003.</p>

<p>What&rsquo;s interesting about this DVD (I really wish they would release a blu-ray) is that it has interactive camera angles during multiple titles.  You are able to &ldquo;switch videos streams&rdquo; to a different camera angles.  Pretty cool.</p>

<p>With Matroska, I retained these video angles within the single MKV file I created of the DVD when I ripped it.  Given though, I didn&rsquo;t copy the &ldquo;cue markers&rdquo; overlay from the original DVD viewing.  You kind of have to know when you can change angles, and you can select a different video stream while playing.</p>

<h2>Subtitles</h2>

<p>This one is especially important to my family.  With a spouse of a different nationality, English sub-titles are a near must.</p>

<p>The other formats have to &ldquo;burn-in&rdquo; sub-titles on-top of the video, removing the option to turn it off.  Yes, many decoders allow you to add an .srt file alongside the MP4 and it will overlay the subtitles (if you get the right one, and if it is in sync with its time codes).</p>

<p>Again, thanks to Matroska&rsquo;s layers, this is only a matter of adding (or removing, or reording) the subtitle tracks that are part of the MKV layers.</p>

<p>Don&rsquo;t like the Dutch sub-titles as default?  Reorder them, or remove them.</p>

<h2>MKV is open source and well documented</h2>

<p>That&rsquo;s right.  No copyright or patents to infringe on.  The perhaps most importantly, the container format is very well documented allowing for anyone to create a set of tools themselves.</p>

<p>It is a real shame that the big players ignore this format, and it is up to us end-users to hack our devices to play them.</p>

<h2>Besides, I can always convert to any format later</h2>

<p>Having all the video and audio streams alongside the closed caption allows me to convert my backups of MKVs into any format I like in the future.</p>

<p>Once such tool is <a href="http://handbrake.fr/">Handbrake</a>, which is a great free and open source app for converting MKVs into any format.  An example is is the Android Tablet profile they have which takes a 15 GB movie and compresses it down to a 1.8 GB file (for the kiddo&rsquo;s tablet).</p>

<h2>A callout to Microsoft, Apple and Google</h2>

<p>Why hasn&rsquo;t MKV gone mainstream?  Why hasn&rsquo;t one of these companies openly embraced this superior format?</p>

<p>The answer is simple: copyright and encryption.  The Matroska format does not support either with its free and open container formats; and therefore, no media partner (MPAA) will ever support a company that openly embraces a format that splays their precious video and audio for all to see and use.</p>

<h2>Handle it myself</h2>

<p>So that leaves me, a lone person, burdened to create my own Matroska MKV containers myself.  More cumbersome is the annoyance of getting the MKVs to play on multiple devices in different media centers and tables.</p>

<p>It seems every few years I have to <em>re-evaluate</em> my media devices and setup to ensure everything is compatible.  Seems to come around with each new Windows release, since the hunt for decoders and setup starts all over.</p>

<p>Next time, it&rsquo;s Linux once and for all.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
